[
    {
        "correct_answer": "3", 
        "id": 1, 
        "option1": "&lt;bullet&gt; ... &lt;/bullet&gt;", 
        "option2": "&lt;list&gt; ... &lt;/list&gt;", 
        "option3": "&lt;ul&gt; ... &lt;/ul&gt;", 
        "option4": "&lt;ol&gt; ...&lt;/ol&gt;", 
        "question": "Which tag is used to lists the items with bullets?"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "2", 
        "id": 2, 
        "option1": "PUT", 
        "option2": "SAVE", 
        "option3": "OPTIONS", 
        "option4": "HEAD", 
        "question": "Which of the following is not a valid HTTP method?"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "4", 
        "id": 3, 
        "option1": "Extensible Server Scripting", 
        "option2": "No Scripting Support", 
        "option3": "XSS Site Scripting", 
        "option4": "Cross Site Scripting", 
        "question": "What does XSS stand for?"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "1", 
        "id": 4, 
        "option1": "123.45.67.89", 
        "option2": "192.168.12.34", 
        "option3": "10.0.0.1", 
        "option4": "127.0.1.1", 
        "question": "Which of the following IP address is not reserved for private use?"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "2", 
        "id": 5, 
        "option1": "HTTP", 
        "option2": "UDP", 
        "option3": "FTP", 
        "option4": "SMTP", 
        "question": "TLS cannot be used along with which of the following?"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "1", 
        "id": 6, 
        "option1": "A virtual table that can be accessed via SQL commands", 
        "option2": "A virtual table that cannot be accessed via SQL commands", 
        "option3": "A base table that can be accessed via SQL commands", 
        "option4": "A base table that cannot be accessed via SQL commands", 
        "question": "What is a view?"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "2", 
        "id": 7, 
        "option1": "Atomicity", 
        "option2": "Credibility", 
        "option3": "Isolation", 
        "option4": "Durability", 
        "question": "Which is not one of ACID properties of an RDBMS"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "3", 
        "id": 8, 
        "option1": "ORDER BY", 
        "option2": "UPDATE", 
        "option3": "GROUP BY", 
        "option4": "None of the above", 
        "question": "In SQL, HAVING clause cannot be used without ______?"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "4", 
        "id": 9, 
        "option1": "UNIQUE", 
        "option2": "PRIMARY", 
        "option3": "DIFFERENT", 
        "option4": "DISTINCT", 
        "question": "To remove duplicate rows from the result set of a SELECT use the following keyword"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "2", 
        "id": 10, 
        "option1": "+A/+BCD", 
        "option2": "ABC+D/+", 
        "option3": "A+BC+/D", 
        "option4": "ABCD/++", 
        "question": "Which of the following is the postfix representation of A + (B + C) / D"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "2", 
        "id": 11, 
        "option1": "&#920;(n)", 
        "option2": "&#920;(log n)", 
        "option3": "&#920;(n^2)", 
        "option4": "&#920;(n log n)", 
        "question": "In a binary search tree having n nodes, inserting a new element has an average time complexity of?"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "2", 
        "id": 12, 
        "option1": "for relatively permanent collections of data ", 
        "option2": "for the size of the structure and the data in the structure are constantly changing", 
        "option3": "for both of above situation ", 
        "option4": "for none of above situation", 
        "question": "Linked lists are best suited "
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "1", 
        "id": 13, 
        "option1": "1,5", 
        "option2": "5,1", 
        "option3": "5,5", 
        "option4": "1,1", 
        "question": "<code>#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;<br>#include&lt;iostream&gt;<br>using namespace std;<br>int main()<br> {<br>     int a;<br>     a=1,2,3,5;<br>     cout&lt;&lt;a;<br>     a=(1,2,3,5);<br>     cout&lt;&lt;a;<br>     return 0;<br> }</code>"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "4", 
        "id": 14, 
        "option1": "point", 
        "option2": "print nothing", 
        "option3": "Run Time error", 
        "option4": "compilation error", 
        "question": "<code>#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;<br>void main(){<br>    int a=5,b=10,c=1;<br>    if(a&&b>c){<br>         printf(\"point\");<br>    }<br>    else{<br>         break;<br>   }<br>}</code>"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "2", 
        "id": 15, 
        "option1": "0", 
        "option2": "1", 
        "option3": "4", 
        "option4": "none", 
        "question": "<code>#include&lt;iostream&gt;<br>struct value<br>{<br><br>}bit;<br><br>int main()<br>{<br>        std::cout&lt;&lt;sizeof(bit);<br>        return 0;<br>}</code>"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "4", 
        "id": 16, 
        "option1": "x=0", 
        "option2": "x=1", 
        "option3": "x=3", 
        "option4": "x=4", 
        "question": "<code>int x = 0;<br /> for (x=1; x&lt;4; x++); <br />printf(\"x=%d\\n\", x);</code>"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "2", 
        "id": 17, 
        "option1": "144", 
        "option2": "32", 
        "option3": "24", 
        "option4": "22", 
        "question": "<code>#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;<br>#define max 10+2<br>int main(){ <br>   int i; <br>   i=max*max; <br>   printf(\"%d\",i); <br>   return 0;<br>}</code>"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "1", 
        "id": 18, 
        "option1": "1  2  12", 
        "option2": "2", 
        "option3": "\"Hello world\" | wc", 
        "option4": "Hello World", 
        "question": "What is the output of the following linux command? <code>echo \"Hello world\" | wc</code> "
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "4", 
        "id": 19, 
        "option1": "user", 
        "option2": "group", 
        "option3": "other", 
        "option4": "root", 
        "question": "Which of the following is not a valid scope for setting file permission?"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "3", 
        "id": 20, 
        "option1": "ROM", 
        "option2": "RAM", 
        "option3": "Hard disk", 
        "option4": "CPU", 
        "question": "Swap area is located in?"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "4", 
        "id": 21, 
        "option1": "Memory management", 
        "option2": "Process management", 
        "option3": "Disk management", 
        "option4": "Reference Counting", 
        "question": "Which of the following is not done by the operating system?"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "1", 
        "id": 22, 
        "option1": "to prevent deadlock in operating systems ", 
        "option2": "to detect deadlock in operating systems", 
        "option3": "to rectify a deadlocked state ", 
        "option4": "none of the above", 
        "question": "The Banker's algorithm is used"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "1", 
        "id": 23, 
        "option1": "Encapsulation", 
        "option2": "Abstraction", 
        "option3": "Polymorphism", 
        "option4": "None of the above", 
        "question": "<code>public class Car<br>{<br>  public char color;<br><br>  public char getColor()<br>  {<br>    return color;<br>  }<br><br>  public void setColor(char color)<br>  {<br>    this.color = color;<br>  }<br>}<br><br>public class MyCar<br>{<br>    private Car car = null;<br><br>    public MyCar()<br>    {<br>        this.car = new Car();<br>        car.color = 'R';<br>    }<br>}<br></code><br>Which OOPS principle does the above code violate?"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "3", 
        "id": 24, 
        "option1": "Super class", 
        "option2": "Sub class", 
        "option3": "Abstract class", 
        "option4": "Inner class", 
        "question": "Which of the following type of class cannot be instantiated directly?"
    }, 
    {
        "correct_answer": "3", 
        "id": 25, 
        "option1": "An abstract representation of something with certain properties", 
        "option2": "A concrete  representation of something with certain properties", 
        "option3": "An abstract representation of something with certain properties and abilities", 
        "option4": "A concrete representation of something with certain properties and abilities", 
        "question": "What is a class?"
    }
]
